Sumeet Bajaj

System Analyst

Hyderabad, Telangana, India sumeet.bajaj03@gmail.com +91-9096971147

Summary

An accomplished and collaborative System Analyst with 6+ years experience in iOS application development as an iOS developer, well versed in using Xcode, iPhone SDK and CocoaTouch framework. Responsibilities include ensuring that proper technical vision and software engineering processes are implemented on all projects incorporating best practices.

Skills & Expertise

- Swift
- Objective-C
- iOS Development
- iPhone & iPad
- Cocoa Touch
- Core Data

- MySQL
- C++
- Python (Basic)
- Angular (Basic)
- Unit Testing
- Test Cases

Experience

Ivy Comptech Pvt. Ltd. - Hyderabad, India

October 2017 - Present (2 years 11 months)

- System Analyst Jan 2020 Present (8 months)
 - Collaborating with Business Analysts, Project Leads and Project Managers to resolve issues and ensure solutions are viable.
 - Worked collaboratively and professionally with other teams to achieve goals
 - Technical guidance on specifications and troubleshooting/conflict resolution
 - Collaborate with a team to define, design, and release new features.
- Senior Software Engineer Jan 2019 Dec 2019 (1 year)
 - Maintaining and upgrading existing apps as required
 - Development and Maintenance of mobile offerings for online gaming (Sports & Casino).
 - o iTunes Automation to upload and fetch app status
 - Developing dynamic framework for Casino Apps.
- Software Engineer Oct 2017 Dec 2018 (1 year 3 months)
 - Integration of REST API web-services and JSON parsing.
 - Integrating new features of betting for Sports Apps.
 - Developed dynamic framework to send apps log on Kibana (elasticsearch).

Mobisoft Infotech Pvt. Ltd. - Pune, India

January 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 9 months)

Software Engineer

- o Designing applications UI using Storyboards, Pure Layout and Auto-Layout
- Integration of REST API web-services and JSON parsing.
- Helped define and design the iOS applications.
- Manage iTunes/Developer portal.
- Improving, refactoring and stabilising code
- App database maintenance, Bug fixing.

Mindbowser Infosolutions Pvt. Ltd. - Pune, India

June 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 7 months)

Associate Software Engineer

- Understanding client requirements and conveying to the team.
- o Designing applications UI using Storyboards and Auto-Layout
- Manage iTunes/Developer portal.
- Preparing Specification Document, Timelines.
- App database maintenance, Bug fixing.
- Social Media logins such as Facebook, Twitter, etc

Certification

 Certified in 'iPhone Application Development' by 'BitCode Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Pune'.

Education

R C Patel Institute of Technology

Bachelor's Degree, Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering, 2008 - 2012 Grade: 66%

K.R Kotkar Junior. College

High School, Computer Science, 2006 - 2008

Grade: 78.50%

Projects

Bwin (Casino) (May 2018 - Jan 2019)

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/bwin-online-casino-games/id952328581?ls=1&mt=8

Bwin Casino - an app provides online casino games like Roulette, Blackjack, Slots, etc.

Bwin (Sports) (Oct 2017 - Aug 2018)

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/bwin-sports-betting/id393760245?ls=1&mt=8

Bwin Sports - an app provides online betting solutions for sports like football, tennis, horse racing, etc.

Canvera Partner (May 2016 - Sep 2017)

https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/canvera-partner/id1187884827?mt=8

Canvera Partner app - an app exclusively for photographers and videographers registered with Canvera.

Logistics App (October 2016 - May 2017)

Logistics include two apps, Shipper App(Individual/Corporate) and Driver App. The Shipper App will enable customers to book new shipments, keep track of its shipments and see his history. Whereas Driver App will enable drivers to keep track of requests coming for shipment and also to see his history.

Safe Pet Treats: Pet & Dog Food Ratings & Recall (June 2016 - September 2016)

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/safe-pet-treats/id1023344412?mt=8

Scan pet food barcodes right from the store to determine if the product is recalled by the FDA or if it is safe. If recalled, report the product anonymously to the FDA in less than 10 seconds. If it is safe, cost effective alternatives will become available to you. Ability to search our recall or ingredient database by typing the product name or UPC number.

Unicornia App (May 2016 - June 2016)

https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/unicornia-app/id1112969587?mt=8

Unicornia is a platform which enables startups to connect Venture Capitals locally and globally. It empowers startups to connect with like minded founders locally to enhance ideas.

CD247(1.0) (January 2016 - April 2016)

https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/cd247-concierge-doctor-247/id1112465362?mt=8

Concierge Doctors App (CDA) is a comprehensive mobile application which provides complete medical assistance to the user wherein one can connect with their doctor, keep track of the medication, update symptoms and receive updates on their prescriptions, proactively, book appointments and can schedule their pick-up in a case of medical attention.

eConnect (June 2015 - December 2015)

Connect is an app for your team that has transformed the way you will communicate and collaborate. The best of the best seamlessly integrated into a single app.

youGOvi (1.0) (November 2014 - June 2015)

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/yougovi/id1038799972?ls=1&mt=8

youGOvi is an app where you can participate in your own videos and photos in various running/upcoming competitions in the app. It serves as the judges who vote for the participants. Apps offer random prizes to anyone participating in the creative process using the app.

Friender (1.0) (June 2014 - October 2014)

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/friender-make-new-friends/id1020721151

Friender is an app which matches you with other individuals for the goal to meet up and form friendships. Matches are based on mutual interest in user-specified activities/hobbies, geographic location, and mutual approval of each other. App provides real time chatting between connected users.

Dreamverse (September 2014 – November 2015)

Dreamers is a social networking app where you can create your digital virtual card which help to create your social networks based on interested industries. The card will show you details about the contact, including their profile picture, connection, projects, social interest and social profile info.